A Guide to the Reports from the Office of the Associate Dean of the Medical School 1972-1977
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
Reports from the Office of the Associate Dean of the Medical School 1972-1977
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
ms-24
The Collection has two Hollinger boxes of processed materials.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Dr. James W. Craig (July 17, 1989)
Biographical/Historical Information
The Collection is a valuable source for the understanding of the history of the University of Virginia Medical Center from 1972 to 1977. In this period, the University Medical Center was taking steps toward not only the enlargement of its resources - facilities, personnel, and finance - but also its major programs - education, research, and patient care. The beginning of the Family Practice Primary Care Curriculum in 1975 and the projects for the expansion of existing hospital buildings and purchase of the Towers Hospital were remarkable developments in this period. All these projects were planned based on the UVA Medical Center's wide-ranging self-surveys and implemented under the guidance of William R. Drucker, Dean of the School of Medicine and James W. Craig, Associate Dean of the School of Medicine.
Collection materials were donated by James W. Craig in 1989. Dr. Craig joined the School of Medicine at the University of Virginia in 1972 as Professor of Internal Medicine and Associate Dean of the School of Medicine. This Collection reflects major developments of the Medical Center in his earlier career at the University of Virginia.
Scope and Content
This Collection contains important reports on the University of Virginia Medical Center from 1972 to 1977. The Collection documents extensive information on the Medical Center in this period, its organization, administration, educational programs, faculty, student, library system, finances, medical center facilities, major activities, graduate program, clinical activities, admission data, etc. Of Particular interest are documents on the Family Practice Primary Care Curriculum that was planned and organized by James W. Craig in 1975. The Collection also includes materials on the Medical Center's expansion project including the purchase of the Towers Hospital.
Arrangement
The Collection is arranged in chronological order.
Contents List
- Shortage of Family Physicians 1972
- Affiliated Medical School Program to Increase Health Manpower 1972
- The Medical Center Master Plan 1974
- Self-Study Report 1973-4
- Selected Activities, 1974-75 1974-75
- Self-Study Summary Report 1974
- Reports of the Survey 1974
- Family Practice Curriculum 1975-76
- Selected Activities 1975-76
- Primary Care Teaching Facility Increment II 1975
- Evaluation of the Financial Feasibility of Purchasing the Towers Hospital 1975
- Decades of No Growth in the University 1975
- Background Data for Long-Range Planning 1975
- Family Practice Primary Care Curriculum for Undergraduate Students 1977